

Jem Walker

Translation & Interpretation

+1 (720) 548-0171

jem@jemwalker.co

Working Languages

A English

(UK and US varieties)

B French

C Spanish

Skills

- Translation
- Interpretation (consec. and simul. including RSI)
- MT post-editing
- Proofreading
- Research source analysis
- Desktop publishing
- Software
 - CAT tools (Trados, MemoQ, WordFast Pro)
 - Microsoft 365 suite
 - Adobe Creative Cloud
 - Front-end web design (HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery)

Awards

 1st Prize, 15th United Nations St. Jerome Translation Contest (Student), 2020 MIIS-trained conference interpreter and translator with a diligent, curious approach to meeting preparation, experience in project managing and interpreter coordination, and a passion for bridging divides between people. Areas of specialization include information technology (particularly cybersecurity), international relations, and arts and culture. ATA and Colorado Translators' Association member; previous experience in politics and public administration, particularly constituent relations.

Experience

KUDO

New York, New York, USA

Project Manager and Conference Interpreter

Dec 2021—April 2023

- Interpreted remotely for events hosted on KUDO including conferences and meetings organized by Microsoft, Meta, Etsy, the International Council on Mining and Metals and the Skoll Foundation
- Managed KUDO's extensive and varied roster of interpreters and staffed events considering specialization, experience, time zone and client preferences such as AllC membership or governmental qualifications
- Contributed to the continued and rapid growth of a key player in the language services sector by participating in product development
- Liaised with clients to understand and meet their language needs and educated them about the world of remote simultaneous interpretation

Freelance Interpreter and Translator

Denver, Colorado, USA

d.b.a. Jem Walker Translation & Interpretation

May 2021—Present

- Provided French-English translation and interpretation services to a wide array of organizations across the world, including the Tokyo 2020+1 Olympics, the International Council of Museums and the Thales Group among others
- Carefully prepared industry-specific terminology and knowledge for every assignment
- Proactively adapted to different clients' linguistic and logistical needs to make communication as effortless as possible in a variety of circumstances
- Continued to focus on professional and skills development to bring bespoke, high-quality language services to clients

Asiatis Translation Agency

Intern

Montréal, Québec, Canada

Jun—Sep 2020

 Translated and proofread various academic and technical texts as well as participating in video game localization projects

Office of the Governor of Colorado

Denver, Colorado, USA

Intern, later Administrative Assistant/Citizens'

Sep 2018—Jun 2019

Advocate, then Scheduling Assistant

- Directly engaged with constituents (in-person and via correspondence) and provided operational support
- Created scheduling processes and worked with stakeholders to ensure optimal planning of the Governor's time

Education

Middlebury Institute of International Studies

MA Translation and Interpretation (FR-EN)

Monterey, California, USA

2019-2021

University of Leeds

BA French and Politics (2:1 classification)

Leeds, UK 2014—2018

Korea University

Intl. Summer Campus (US Foreign Pol. & Korean)

Seoul, Republic of Korea

2015